so sí hay un range ahí .
mmhm .
donde los policías practican .
y y la gente que están los trainees the police trainees .
they do it every day .
so when you come here don't be afraid if you hear it .
because you know they're practicing .
yeah yeah they have to put these earphones .
porque si no se puede quedar uno sordo .
really ?
pero aquí no se oye mucho .
absolutely se puede quedar uno sordo .
when .
cuando yo estoy entrando aquí sometimes I hear it .
but it' not so loud because the range is all the way over there .
yeah .
which is great .
I imagine if we were right there that would be a problem .
yeah .
but there' a lot of distance .
so I don't think it' a problem .
no no no it' not a problem .
pero if you do it every day you you suppose to you know for protection .
that' a good idea .
yeah .
but they have like like little dummies .
and I think you're supposed to like target them or something .
that is the target right ?
yeah .
yeah I used to do that .
entonces &=mumbles si caminas un poco más if you walk a little further you'll see they're building and like an exercise path for the police officials or police trainees actually .
entonces tienes que brincar tienes que ir .
obstacle courses .
sí exactamente .
oh my god .
entonces lo tienen ahí entonces there' a lot of construction going around here .
so I asked what was happening .
and they said that the the the corrections is coming and also F_B_I .
oh my goodness so we're expanding .
exactly .
qué bueno .
es bueno tener un lugar donde uno pueda crecer porque digamos ahora estás aquí .
pero mañana puedes estar en otra posición .
exacto uno nunca sabe .
y todas las chicas aquí son bien inteligentes .
sí .
they're very smart .
and they all have background in what they do which is broadcasting videos .
wow .
and like actually recording .
and editing and all that stuff .
and it' gonna be great trying to learn from them because they're all experts .
so I'm kind of looking forward to doing that .
always learn from the experts .
exactly .
you can always become good yourself .
well yeah they're good trainers .
so I I have faith that I'll be able to do it eventually .
y entonces allá entonces en el en el edificio cien .
está la command staff .
ahí está el lieutenant .
ahí está el major .
so for instance I report to the lieutenant .
.
and the whole place reports to the major .
they report to different people .
right .
but he' the one in charge ultimately .
aquí hay una muchacha que se llama Ana@:eng que she' very sweet .
y entonces está encinta .
oh@:eng .
y y no va poder venir she' not gonna be able to come in for another seven months .
but everybody reports to her .
but I I report to the to the lieutenant which is in the command staff .
she' so beautiful .
she' very young .
una muchacha bien joven bien bonita .
y muy capacitada .
gracias a dios que dios la bendiga .
exacto .
because you know being a mother is no easy task .
no that I know .
but it' the best that anybody could experience in life .
well you you have a lot of experience being a .
you reared us all .
yeah .
you had six of us .
and you put us all through school .
.
a mí me ayudaste increíblemente .
I probably could never have done anything without you .
thank you sis .
you're welcome mamita .
and now you're putting Carmencita@:eng my daughter through school which is not an easy task either .
and your children too .
I tell you I think that now is is difficult .
it' very difficult nowadays porque es que la calle está mala .
&=yawn .
no todo está malo .
las muchachas no saben portarse bien porque las muchachas hoy en día it it' a problem .
exactamente .
huh .
y .
yo no entiendo a estas muchachas hoy en día .
and my daughter now is using you know .
I got her the phone as a protection when she goes to school whatever she has to call but they're text messaging .
yeah now they don't even have to use your minutes .
es todo es text message .
exacto .
yo yo te digo la verdad que ahora vamos a tener que hacer algo para saber qué es lo que está hablando en ese text message .
I'm looking yo lo yo lo miro .
sí ?
I have to check my son you know .
you don't you haven't checked at all ?
yo no .
no .
so when do you plan to ?
no I'm gonna ask Ivan@:eng to do it for me porque .
you porque tú no lo puedes hacer you can't go to it and start checking this ?
es que he is such a an advanced technologically advanced .
his his phone .
yeah y yo no sé ni cómo prenderlo &=grunt .
porque el teléfono mío no el teléfono mío tú sabes .
no pero el tuyo sí sabe .
tú sabes bastante de eso .
aunque no lo creas tú entiendes bastante .
pero yo como nunca me interesé en eso de text message yo ahora a quién voy a hablarle ?
bueno tú tiene() mucha gente que te quiere .
en text message .
sí pero .
but it takes time it' very tedious .
yeah .
y y entonces están usando los dedos .
eso de los dedos va a dar artritis .
todo el día en eso oh my god .
fíjate que en mi teléfono tanto que yo marco que ya se me está acabando en en the face of my phone .
really ?
it' it' already smeared .
entonces el problema es que .
see look the number eight it' like it' all messed up .
y entonces en qué letra entonces cuando uno tiene que marcar la letra uno no sabe .
pero los niños hoy en día they memorize it .
Carmencita@:eng is really fast .
que que number seven is a I don't know I_G_T whatever .
Carmencita@:eng is so fast on that on that email or the text messaging on her phone .
she'll answer faster to a text message than to answer her phone .
I think so .
I'm serious .
and they do this all day so now .
and was telling me that since she is so close to that phone that another way to get to her so she behaves is say to her +".
+" you know if you if you miss behave .
because you know she has a tendency with her friends and everythings .
+" then what they're gonna take the phone away when you get name from school you can't text message .
and then then she says how quickly she' gonna be behave because she wants to do it .
you know I wish that that would be a solution to the problem .
but it' a a &=mumble at least it' a suggestion .
you know taking away .
but what do you say ?
you know the the the .
you you have psychology .
what what what' the best way ?
my philosophy is totally different that .
I believe in you know look for something that she' doing right .
and reward her .
yeah but what about the stuff that she' doing negative +/?
some how .
how do you take that away ?
you have to find a way to to either overlook it .
and then reframe the whole circumstances .
tienes que buscarle la onda porque es que toda la gente en psicología sabe que que eso no trabaja .
bueno por ejemplo .
taking away taking away taking away .
por ejemplo hace dos días ella estaba bien bien grosera .
she was extremely nasty .
that' not good .
so we're gonna punish her this weekend .
she can't go out .
she she could go out .
but she can't be with her friends which is that' a real punishment .
you know puede ser .
yeah that that to me that kind of punishment is like when you have finished all your recourses .
to be with her friends not .
to reframe the circumstances .
you've gotta find ways that she would wanna do it voluntarily to behave .
to to get her clothing out .
.
er finding ways .
well I think the fact that she wants to be with her friends every weekend .
and if and I'm not letting her do it this weekend because she didn't behave .
I don't think she'll be she'll be nasty again .
I think that she will be .
you do ?
ok let' try .
let' use it as a as a test .
try it try it .
try it .
I mean some times you have to use that kind of um ...
+training .
+, you know training yeah .
a a lo mejor trabajo contigo .
pero yo trato yo trato lo máximo de no usar esa técnica .
so que tú dame un ejemplo .
vamos a suponer que tu hijo te cuenta te contesta mal .
no .
qué tú haces ?
well many times I give him the silent treatment .
for how long tú no le hablas ?
bueno no I give him the silent treatment .
and he he never gets the silent treatment porque se porta bien .
pero cuánto ?
un minuto día o hora ?
no .
instantáneamente ya él sabe que yo estoy disgustada .
y and he'll ask me +"/.
+" are you mad at me ?
I say +"/.
+" yeah I am .
+" what do you expect ?
+" you want me to have a smile on my face ?
mmhm .
but we have a very good communication thank god .
and he knows that I'll you know do whatever I can to support him .
yeah but like if he :n but if he answers you nasty .
and he goes into his room .
I say you know +"/.
+" is that necessary ?
I say +"/.
we we in this household believe in respect .
and we try to work it out .
hablando se entiende la gente .
claro .
pero hasta ahora because él nada más tiene que quince añitos va para dieciséis next month .
a hundred and twenty god willing .
dios se lo bendiga .
thank you .
and you know they go through some kind of osmosis when they hit sixteen .
sixteen seventeen .
&=laugh .
so you know he said to me the other day +"/.
+" oh you know mother .
+" you're the greatest .
that was nice .
yeah .
que te dijo eso .
él siempre me da cumplidos así .
so I said to him +"/.
+" talk to me in two more years .
&=laugh .
because you plan to what ?
well because they go through this osmosis .
bring in the rains .
then hey what what happened to the to most kids ?
exactly .
no I'm praying that it won't happen to my kid .
I mean .
my oldest son went through a a little bit once he got to the point que estaba dating .
uhuh .
and a that seems to be a problem .
pero yo I don't remember Armand@:eng dating except Muni@:eng .
yeah .
did he when he went away you didn't see him .
no no he was a he went to Europe .
pero a quién más he dated here .
aquí nunca salió con nadie .
yeah he used to have some friends .
he did ?
yeah .
but the the point to be made is thank god que era serio .
mmhm .
y con todo y eso he was problematic .
staying up late sixteen seventeen .
and he went to religious school .
yeah ahora Carmencita@:eng likes to stay up late too .
but she' like on the computer .
or watching T_V .
.
that' ok .
it' kid stuff .
you know you know weekends whatever .
and during the week también yo últimamente la estoy acostando más temprano .
pero no es fácil because she doesn't wanna go to sleep .
and her friends are text_messaging her .
well I would say you know comes nine o'clock nine thirty because she is only eleven .
so nine thirty is the latest .
the phone gets shut off .
the lights go off .
the Tv goes off .
and everybody goes into the sac .
it' time to go to sleep .
I think that if you program kids like that early in life like my son right now .
he automatically can he can't stay up .
está cansado .
for example now que he' into football .
cómo estaba en eso he plays everyday football ?
everyday they do training at six in the morning .
so it' a football team for the school ?
yeah .
wow@:eng that' interesting .
it' the first one in the nation .
really ?
from a religious school .
wow@:eng so that' good that he' part of it .
he' thrilled .
and .
so what position is he in now ?
I don't know yet .
but he' the guy that' supposed to stop them from moving .
did they .
he' like defence I think .
yeah I don't know .
he said first lineman .
I don't know much about I don't know yo tampoco conozco mucho football@:eng .
I think he told me first lineman .
he says +"/.
+" mommy you would be so proud of me .
I know .
I said +".
+" I'm proud of you know .
exactly .
because of course I don't what him to play .
I know because you don't want to him to break anything god forbid .
but you know what ?
I don't wanna stifle him .
que la vida hay que hacer de todo un poco .
yo nunca aprendí a nadar ni roller_skate .
ni ni ni ni no hice muchas cosas en mi vida because .
yo tampoco .
swimming I I should have learned how to swim .
swimming oh my god that' a perfect .
I regretted so much .
yeah that' the perfect thing to do when you get older .
and you know .
but when you get older you're over the hill .
perfect thing to do it when you get when you're younger .
yeah but yeah .
I know but I'm saying .
como Carmencita@:eng se tiene que aprender .
she has to learn .
let' talk a little bit about Carmencita@:eng .
tiene que aprender .
mother insinuated that I should put her in camp this year .
I don't think so .
I told her I rather pay you and you take her .
she can come with me any time .
because .
pero you know she likes .
last year we had a great time .
yeah .
because mother was saying .
we .
because mother maybe because mummy no la puede cuidar .
mamá no la puede cuidar .
yo entiendo .
it' a conflict .
pero a mí no me gustaría ponerla en camp por las amigas .
yeah .
yo te voy a decir una cosa las amigas .
the further away .
por eso ella se puso brava conmigo .
porque la amiguita esta que yo vi que estaba con el muchacho ahí .
what a stressful situation for that guy .
he' in elementary school .
and the girl is making advances towards him .
you know what is the guy supposed to do .
y qué hizo el muchachito ?
qué podía hacer el pobre ?
se estaba tranquilo .
no hizo nada .
estaba tranquilo .
ella cogió la mano del muchachito .
se la puso en la en la pierna de ella .
y qué hizo él ?
la dejó ahí .
pobrecito what was he supposed .
pobrecito no .
it' a it' a lot of stress for boys because these girls they don't know how to behave .
they don't .
pero gracias a dios Carmencita@:eng no está en eso .
bueno .
no yo no he visto .
no no yo tampoco .
entonces las otras madres me dijeron que tampoco está que la están mirando y tampoco está en eso .
pero .
pero eso nada yo te digo la verdad .
yo estaba sorprendida .
yo creo que hoy la voy a sorprender porque ella va ir al parque hoy she' gonna go to the park today .
yeah .
and I leave at four which is great .
I love the hours here .
oh thank god .
from eight to four .
well you start early anyway .
well there gonna be times I have to stay like when they're doing stuff .
you know I might have to stay .
but that' not not everyday .
and sometimes when they have graduations I have to stay to help them whatever .
yeah .
but that' not every day .
so like once every two or three months .
thank god this is a blessing because people that are mothers .
yeah .
you can't you've gotta be on the top of these kids .
but today she wants to go to the park because I told her +"/.
+" I let you go today to the park .
+" Friday Saturday and Sunday you gotta be you know doing your .
+" you've got when do you think you're gonna finish your project with her ?
tomorrow you should work on it the all day .
well you you see how good she is with the computer man .
I know she is .
did you do .
but I didn't see any of the research under the three people or the four people .
yeah we have we have research but not enough .
not enough .
and I think the pictures looked too big .
she brought me a book .
me trajo un libro que ella lo había leído when she was in third grade I think .
she did ?
really ?
pero las fotos vas a tener que hacerlas más chiquitas para que +"/.
no ella lo quiere así grande .
pero cómo si no te puede flip ?
no ella no quiere .
ella dice que la maestra lo hizo así .
and I said +"/.
really ?
ok .
+" fine .
that' fine .
I say +"/.
+" you know what ?
+" the instructions no sirven because te dicen que lo pongas arriba y la maestra dijo que lo ponga abajo .
exacto .
what kind of instructions are that ?
I don't know sister .
thank god that you're a teacher .
oh my god .
and praise the lord que you know what you're doing with her praise god .
praise god yeah .
so due tomorrow can you just work on it ?
do you think you can just work on it all day with her ?
yeah we'll work on it .
she' very good .
if you finish tomorrow then you're home free with that .
but then there' a science project .
you already know more or less what you're gonna do with her ?
yeah we know what we're gonna do .
how long will the science project take ?
I don't know .
but you know what they do is for the parents to do their work .
no I know that .
I know that .
you know how many projects ella hizo ...
tantos proyectos que ha hecho .
what kind of a feedback did you get ?
nothing .
what kind of a feedback ?
but they they're ridiculous .
did they tell you when the science project is due or not ?
er in April the first day that you they get back from their vacation .
no this is due .
this is due .
this one' due .
but when is the science project due ?
it' probably in may .
maybe in may ?
may .
so did you wanna take a break ?
or did you wanna start doing it ?
no we wanna finish it because I'm going on vacation .
no you're gonna you're gonna start the science project too ?
yeah .
ok@:eng so but finish this one first .
and then work on the science project with her .
yeah .
we have the whole week to do that .
the science and this one .
well finish this one first .
yeah .
this one' due .
mmhm .
yo le dijo que ella que ella tiene que darle muchas gracias a dios que te tiene a ti sister porque tú eres una mujer muy muy educada .
no she' good .
ella es buena .
y eres maestra de profession .
and you know what you're doing .
you know these are ...
kids don't know .
they don't know whether they're coming or going .
it' a joke .
it' supposed to be fun .
pero you know what the way they do it .
sí pero these teachers assigning these projects the kids don't even know if they're coming or going .
what do they expect ?
I don't know if they are gonna remember any of this stuff down the line .
maybe they will .
maybe these things are good .
so getting back to Carmencita@:eng .
yeah .
do you wanna take care of her for the summer then ?
and I'll just give you something for that .
yeah .
&=coughing .
I'm thinking ...
it' like three months right .
so er ...
we can work at it .
ahora yo no sé me gustaría que ella aprendiera a nadar .
well maybe you could take her .
you know I I'm gonna see maybe maybe .
I'll give you the money for that .
if Armand@:eng finds a job I need him to get to work .
tu hijo ?
yeah .
qué tú quieres que haga ?
anything I'm gonna put him in Publix@:eng anywhere .
because last year he worked with Nancy@:eng .
but this year I don't know .
y este año no puede trabajar .
no .
are they cutting back personnel pues no hay dinero .
oh .
yeah .
no hay dinero en ninguna parte .
y el stress level oye .
él tiene dieciséis años ya .
ya .
él puede trabajar en la biblioteca también .
sería un buen trabajo then .
well because of the allergies no me gustaría .
los libros .
tú sabes dust mites he' very allergic .
what so what did you have in mind for him ?
I don't know .
I said Publix@:eng .
you want him to work at Publix@:eng in in in the street there ninety fifty street by the house ?
yeah you know anybody there ?
I could go help you .
I could go talk for you .
yeah good .
not that you can't .
I mean you do it because you talk just as well .
well I applied last year .
pero it was very late .
y qué te dijeron ?
and they already had hired todo el mundo que ellos necesitaban .
we can go .
and find out .
so .
we can go and ...
because I'm when I'm there I can enquire for the summer .
yeah .
like what hours .
they make you go .
and fill out this application .
como todas las horas tú quieres que él trabaje .
.
I I could drop him off .
pick up Carmencita@:eng .
pick up Armand@:eng .
drop off Carmencita@:eng .
no conflict of interest .
&=laugh .
pero a qué hora más o menos like from eight to or nine ?
nine .
nine to ...
nine to four .
that' good .
it' a whole day .
day .
nine to five .
I I can ask I can ask .
when I'm there next time I voy a hablar con el manager a preguntarle .
he' sixteen years old no@:eng ?
yeah .
yeah he' sixteen .
he'll be sixteen April thirtieth .
it' a great location .
yeah I like it .
and you know the supervision there probably is better than other places .
exacto .
y al lado de la casa .
vamos a ver .
it' not too far from the house .
no .
está bueno .
maybe they can teach him how to be a cashier instead of a bag boy ?
but you want him to be a stock boy ?
whatever .
I don't care .
if he were if he did a cashier .
I don't want him to be a stock boy .
but cashier but you know .
but usually they have er women doing cashier .
do they no they have some guys .
I've never seen a guy there .
I don't think I've seen a guy there .
the bag boys .
yeah the bag boys are guys .
do you want me to have requests ?
and they they're really handicapped the ones that are bag boys .
yeah .
do you want me to request to see if they can train him how to be a cashier ?
he' good in math .
no I know .
but will he be bored with that ?
cashier ?
I don't know .
if not then what is it left the stock or there' the deli .
oh he would like that .
to make sandwiches .
but you can't work in there until you are eighteen .
oh really so you've done your homework .
yeah .
&=laughing .
te conoce .
only why .
I tell you why .
porque si se cortan .
sí .
.
puede pasar algo .
así a mí no me gustan .
I didn't think about the machines .
the machine .
pero I thought maybe instead of the machine then he likes er baking .
but you can't .
not even in the baking section ?
you gotta be eighteen .
no se puede hacer ?
porque él sabe hacerlo .
y él tiene todas las herramientas .
no que they have their own anyways so ...
he loves it .
le encanta baking .
what did you think about the the brownies ?
oh they were outstanding .
I ate them all .
and then mother goes +"/.
+" oh there' some more left .
qué rico .
and then I go +"/.
+" no ya yo me lo comí .
y entonces me lo me lo comí todo un día siguiente al otro .
y cuando Carmencita fue dice +"/.
+" nada yo te todo .
see I love sweets .
that' my problem sister .
you don't like sweets as much as I do .
I mean I love sweets .
no I can take it or leave it .
no me no me hace nada anyway .
lo que sí hace es ponerte gorda .
no yo sé .
and I don't need that .
no no not at all .
we don't .
none of us need that .
I know .
and I was reading you know que sugar is bad even for cancer because the cancer cells .
really ?
yeah they feed on sugar .
mmhm .
so that' not good .
es mejor .
yo no sabía .
you should tell that to Carmencita@:eng because Carmencita@:eng loves sugar .
.
really ?
we're gonna .
.
tienes que decir .
sí pero tienes que decírselo .
sí esa parte yo no sabía .
maybe now for sure .
that will cure me big time .
.
because I love sweets .
I I had an article that someone sent me en en el internet@:eng .
mmhm .
sí ahí decía todo de eso .
sabes quién lo tiene Marcelo .
really ?
eats a lot of sweets too .
she does ?
have you spoken to her lately ?
yeah .
cómo está bien ?
she called me the other day .
yeah happy go lucky .
cuándo vas a ver el apartamento de ella ?
tú sabes you know no tengo tiempo para eso .
tienes que ir porque te vas a .
su mamita .
pero es que a mí no me gusta heights anyway .
no but you gotta go sis .
I'm not kidding .
you have promise me you're gonna go .
go with Carmencita this week coming up .
ok .
maybe .
no you have to !
yeah with with Carmencita@:eng I can go .
yeah go with Carmencita@:eng .
I'll take her to the pool .
yeah maybe you can teach her how to swim porque tiene que saber .
y eso .
I know how to teach .
pero yo no sé nadar bien .
pero ahí ahí no pasa nada anyway .
pero mira a ver si le puedes enseñar porque lo que pasa es que todas las fiestas ahora del summer people are gonna learn people are gonna know how to swim .
and she' the only one who can't go to the parties .
I mean I take her to the parties .
but then she feels like she' left out .
she a drag not to know how to swim man .
hay que saber hay que saber porque estamos surrounded by water .
I I hope ...
I know sis .
you know ?
but I don't know what to tell you porque ella no no se quiere mojar la cara .
y no sé como va a aprender .
y a mí no me gusta el agua fría .
cuando uno va al swimming pool ahí no me gusta .
y si va uno al al mar to the ocean .
no you know what happened at the ocean the other day ?
what happened ?
that when we went to the park all the kids decided they wanted to go into the ocean .
mmhm .
and of course Carmencita@:eng no fue .
fue pero no se metió en el agua .
&=laugh .
and all the kids got sting stung by a .
&=gasp .
men of war ?
yeah .
todos .
llorando y gritando .
y yo estaba feliz que mi hija no había entrado .
no estaba feliz pues they got hurt .
no of course .
y no llamé a las madres para que .
I think you put vinegar no ?
I think was urinating orinando .
or or pee yeah .
it' supposed to .
pero pero todos los niños llorando porque dicen que le dolía mucho .
y Carmencita@:eng tú sabes .
pero esto tampoco no le ayuda a Carmencita@:eng porque le da miedo entrar al agua porque ella tú sabes que le da miedo de todo .
so if she would have got stung that would have been her first experience .
she wouldn't have been going back in the ocean .
I'll tell you that much .
.
oh my god .
pero no tenían el flag out there ?
no .
no ?
there was no flag .
this is by .
yeah .
no tenían un lifeguard ?
no no tenían .
no lifeguard ?
nothing .
that' not good .
no that' terrible .
no not good at all .
so .
yo te digo la verdad mira eso de sting rates .
eso eso es muy peligroso .
y ahora yo no sé qué está pasando .
.
que hasta they are coming down to the shores and oh my god .
it' very scary .
porque yo le tengo mucho respeto al agua .
so the ocean is gonna be off limits for me anyway .
a Nerea@:eng le encanta el agua .
really well you know what ?
now that Luis@:eng is is behaving we should go back on the ocean because I don't think it' gonna be wild .
I hate it .
I hate it too .
but you know he loves his boating .
I know .
and then his kids have been using it .
every weekend los niños de él .
let him go out with his kids .
no I know .
say +"/.
+" honey I'll wait for you here .
&=laugh .
on land .
I'll go to the movies while you are on the ocean .
I'm safe territory .
yeah .
no no no no .
a él le encanta su bote .
ah pero no últimamente no está yendo nada .
mmhm .
a los niños .
they took over his boat .
mmhm .
in a way I'm I'm happy .
yeah let them have it .
you know who likes it ?
no .
my son .
really ?
and .
he even wants to play he wants to learn how to play an airplane .
he does ?
do you know Luis@:eng is a is is is knows how to fly .
yeah .
he has his license and everything .
a mí no me gusta nada de eso .
but I told him +"/.
+" don't go get your .
+" you don't have to renew it .
I yeah .
you have to renew it .
yo le dije +".
+" don't renew anything .
porque yo no me voy airplane with him .
no .
I did it once .
I went on a on an airplane que era chiquitito .
this guy told me that he was a doctor .
he lied about that .
this is when I was single .
oh yeah .
is that ?
Paul@:eng you met my sister right ?
yeah .
Paul@:eng in the refrigerator sweetheart there' a thing called an empanada .
I bought I bought it yesterday .
you weren't here .
have one .
you are gonna love it .
I bought it at a Colombian@:eng restaurant .
oh good .
that' where we are gonna go to lunch today .
yeah good .
un restaurante más rico !
mmhm .
it' Colombian and their empanadas .
they know how to cook .
yeah .
but you cook too sis .
I cook seven days a week .
a mí me gusta cocinar .
see I don't .
a mí me gusta .
I don't because .
although for Luis@:eng like this week I made him some filet_mignon .
hay que hacerlo .
I made him some fillet mignon week .
don't overcook it .
that' all you have to do .
yeah and then I made him a salad .
and Carmencita@:eng of course estaba comiendo su macaroni and cheese .
that' ok .
ella come lo que le gusta .
no come cosas que le que le sean nutritional you know .
bueno está comiendo pizza which is a cheese and a a little bit of the sauce .
yeah .
it' also very fattening .
I know .
the french_fries está comiendo los chicken nuggets .
she likes those .
also fried food .
yeah .
eventually .
she' eating more salads though .
yeah eventually yo creo no sé yo creo que ella va a comenzar a comer mejor .
yeah .
she' eating chicken caesar salad now .
that' good .
that' very good .
so I need to today .
I don't want to go to Publix@:eng and buy her some more chicken caesar .
she loves it .
yeah ?
you know the ones that come bagged ?
yeah .
a ella le encanta comer eso .
es que hoy en día como uno está tan ocupado .
yo cocino en veinte treinta minutos .
pero with the help of a lot of people .
for example you know like for instance today ya yo tengo rosetti@:eng .
it' just it' a pasta that' stuffed .
all I have to do is heat it up put the sauce on top a little bit of sugar .
and I have a meal with a with a salad .
but what' in the pasta cheese ?
yeah it' stuffed shells .
so that' one meal .
y cuánto tú le sirves a todo el mundo ?
so when I say que yo tengo ayuda de otra gente quiero decir que I use frozen vegetables .
&=laughs I thought that you meant that you had helping you .
no are you kidding me ?
I'm serious .
do they ever wash the dishes ?
I .
because yesterday Luis@:eng Luis@:eng was washing the dishes yesterday .
no they never wash them .
I was impressed .
no .
because you know he would never wash dishes before .
they are allergic to water .
yeah .
they never wash the dishes unless of course I say +"/.
+" you know what ?
+" I'm on strike .
+" y no voy a lavar hoy .
+" ahí que se queden las cosas .
oh they don't like when I say that .
right .
I say +"/.
+" how would you like it ?
+" just because I'm a housewife I'm always washing ?
no .
I'm gonna get arthritis god forbid .
no no no no .
no es que me duelen los dedos de verdad !
well the guys should help .
no that' not good .
yo fui al médico .
y le dije +"/.
+" you think this is arthritis ?
me dice +"/.
+" no parece que sea arthritis .
yo le dije +"/.
+" pero doctor I have a terrible pain in my finger .
not good .
so Adrian@:eng says it' the kickboxing .
I shouldn't do kickboxing .
and I love kickboxing !
how could you take kickboxing away from me ?
exactly .
it' my life .
do you love kickboxing ?
&=laughing .
I need to start on my treadmill también .
oh my god .
I I tell you I wish he would go with me .
ahora que Luis@:eng Luis@:eng ha estado ahora .
tú sabes que va a coger otra vez el gas station .
sí .
he got rid of the one in .
gracias a dios .
and he' gonna take one two weeks .
but this time he' gonna have an associate because it' it' very expensive .
I know .
his cousin .
yeah .
so it' very nice .
it' big .
to start he' gonna take one .
and then maybe eventually he'll have another one .
yeah .
so he'll be back at it .
bueno es el negocio de él .
yeah he' good at it .
eso es lo que él él sabe .
él sabe digamos de accounting .
or how much he' gonna make .
and he calculates todas esas cosas .
no he knows .
when it comes to running a store and that' his expertise .
that' his business .
I mean I can ...
and people actually look for him to ask him his opinion .
he' like a consultant .
and I said you should charge !
yeah .
instead of giving free opinion .
advice .
yeah .
gente Cobra@:eng .
dios lo bendiga .
tú sabes él he knows his business .
yes he does .
and the way he conducts himself people look up to him .
yeah he is a very serious guy .
yeah .
he is serious ?
now he is more serious .
pobrecito .
&=laughing .
no he is really serious .
but yesterday we were watching T_V .
&=laughing .
was on he says +"/.
+" did you know anything about Publix@:eng ?
oh .
and I said what .
and then I told him I needed some Ajax@:eng soap .
and he went .
and he got it for me .
oh you know a relationship goes through a lot of different phases .
you know .
I'm trying to sell I mean rent this house .
ay no quieras saber .
I'm going crazy with it .
did you rent it or you didn't ?
no not yet .
eso le queda .
people tell me +"/.
+" oh sí ya voy para allá señora .
y me dejan esperando two three four hours .
y no vienen .
that' terrible .
it' terrible .
so anyway do you have your condo ?
el condo que tú tienes ahí .
tampoco está alquilado .
and the beach ?
yeah .
cuánto tú tú arrentas ese lugar ?
fifteen hundred and it' beautiful inside .
el condo .
es dos cuartos ?
dos cuartos ...
dónde tenía Adrian su apartamento ?
sí pero el mío es mucho más limpio porque está todo limpiecito pintadito .
lo que pasa es que están arreglando .
el edificio o el apartamento ?
el edificio afuera le están poniendo todo nuevo pero no han llegado to my unit .
right .
so you know ...
I mean the only thing that you can really use es el balcón .
so they are gonna put they are gonna put they are gonna put they are gonna put in your unit ?
they are gonna they are gonna fix your unit too ?
yeah the whole thing .
I mean it' astronomical lo que están cobrando .
really ?
for the maintenance alone I'm paying close to a thousand dollars .
see that' what Luis says .
he says it' horrible .
it' not worth it .
listen if you wanna go see it it' a beautiful place sis .
nadie te molesta .
está todo nuevecito adentro .
I know I know that he' gonna see one .
pero los baños no son tan modernos como el que tú tienes aquí en en el condo .
en el condo .
we are supposed to go see one today at six .
because he has to move .
yeah I know .
he because the because the owner can't afford it .
it' in for closure .
&=gasp it is for closure !
so many people are in for closure !
so the owner but the owner hasn't told them anything .
I don't know how many millions of rooms are gonna be in for closures .
but he got the letter from the attorney .
I don't know .
pero parece que hay otros lugares en el en el mismo lugar que a lo mejor va a ser más barato .
porque él está pagando dos mil ahora .
sí .
so he' figured prize .
listen if you wanna move in there I'll give it to you cheaper .
he says you know what because we could get it for a lot cheaper so called them .
y le dijo +"/.
+" ve para acá porque hay un edificio el agua y todo .
vamos a ver cuánto quiere .
si el tipo quiere dos mil dólares le voy a decir que no .
you know aunque yo no lo pago .
lo va a pagar Luis@:eng but you know still .
no pero de todos modos no vale la pena .
yo te digo sinceramente +"/.
+" I think that you both should come and see it .
es lindo .
I'll ask him today .
in fact Luis@:eng se iba a mudar ahí .
iba a vender su casa .
y se iba a mudar ahí .
I think he said que se iba a mudar a un condominium .
sí se iba a mudar ahí porque es bonito .
but what happened ?
that house is beautiful .
he he is not he is not retired yet .
he should .
I know .
if I if I was his age and his money I would have retired .
pero a él ...
pero a él le gusta trabajar .
pero es una estupidez .
he wanted to be this .
he is almost sixty years old already .
how old is he like ...
sixty three I think .
so he should retire and be happy .
.
I think that at sixty five you can retire with a better income .
who cares about the income ?
he he he he is fine .
well this is what this is what he told me .
he should live he should live .
if things would get rough where he is working now ...
then he would retire .
he would give them their working papers .
and he would retire .
tienes mucha razón .
right now you know what ?
a él le gusta la gente que le trabajan .
they look up to him .
él se siente contento ahí aunque tiene mucho trabajo .
no if they respect him that' good .
they respect him .
and you know what ?
when you retire many times you vegetate .
you are throwing the towel .
yeah .
that' what I don't wanna do .
well you are never gonna retire because you are gonna live a hundred and twenty .
and then you have Carmencita'@:eng all of middle school elementary .
&=laughing .
so one more year .
I'm I'm getting this adventure now yeah .
then you have middle school .
and then you have high school .
well I have this invention going that hopefully they will bite .
and if they bite you know I will have an income there .
praise god .
a steady income yeah thank god .
but you are gonna have like a your like a warehouse or something like that ?
no I don't wanna do that .
I just want to sell my ideas .
déjalos que ellos se maten haciendo lo que yo quiero hacer .
de producto .
hacer el producto .
este market it .
sell it .
are you just gonna get the royalties ?
manufacture it .
just royalties .
that' good sis .
if they like my ideas .
yo le dije al tipo yo le dije +"/.
+" you know what the it' needed .
+" it' something that is needed so how could you fail ?
people will buy it .
it' not something that er ...
yeah do you remember that that stupid guy I was recently dating ?
he was saying that he uses gloves .
yeah .
pero que las manos le sudaban mucho .
eso era lo que tú estabas patentando verdad ?
sí .
so entonces eh@:eng I think it would sell .
I know it' gonna sell .
now let' see if the guy bites .
he wrote to me .
but he' not the only one .
no this is the second one I'm approaching .
and what did he say ?
he' a a a big supplier to big big stores .
he manufactures all kinds of stuff .
and what did he say finally ?
so .
I don't know I'm waiting for his response a ver qué me dice .
tú qué crees ?
yo creo que sí .
yo creo que le va a encantar because ...
anything that you decide to do sis is very intelligent .
I I'm banking on that sis .
I really am banking on that because I like to see you know something that I do .
to flourish .
and that everybody will benefit from it .
you are very good .
is gonna work for the rest of his life ?
yeah .
because of the insurance .
yeah the insurance .
el insurance está carísimo .
oh yeah man .
tú te acuerdas cuando yo dejé de trabajar .
I went on Cobra@:eng .
mmhm .
it was it was ridiculous .
it was about a thousand dollars for Carmencita@:eng and I .
no se puede .
no se puede estar sin seguro .
a month !
so how do you do it so that you can retire ?
you really cannot retire .
no you can't retire .
and mm I don't want him to retire either .
&=laughing .
yeah .
most housewives would say that about their husbands .
&=laughing .
you'll drive me crazy .
go to work honey .
yeah he'll drive me nuts .
yeah .
that' er ...
you know .
but he' a good guy .
no no he is .
yeah .
he is .
you know like Luis@:eng you know Luis@:eng just if you just feed Luis@:eng and give him his television he is happy .
right .
they are quiet men .
yeah .
and I don't really have to feed him .
he'll say +"/.
what do you want me to go get you ?
.
so it' not like I have to cook .
that' a blessing .
exactly .
just for that keep him around .
yeah .
exactly .
no .
the other day he was shocked that I said +"/.
+" no I'm gonna make you filet_mignon .
+" you are ?
yeah .
+" are you feeling ok ?
pero no lo molestas sis .
como no molestas .
si él se queda así eso sería un milagro de dios .
sería .
sí .
yo te digo la verdad .
él vino aquí el otro día .
sí .
conoció a a a Lola .
yeah .
so we'll see lo que .
él es buena gente .
yes he is .
yo siempre te lo he dicho .
he is a nice guy .
oh@:eng te dio yo no te di la carta la carta ?
yeah you gave me the letter yeah .
ah sí .
and er ya se la dimos al profesor y todo .
yo estaba haciendo otro para Carmencita .
enseñamelo porque she' gonna need community hours .
oh really ?
sure .
she needs them now .
.
she needs them now for her no sé qué .
you know I think this is so ridiculous .
she had a good over a hundred hours of vodka@:eng .
oh please .
so I made that up .
and I'm making him sign it .
that' all .
yeah .
so ...
oh please .
oh please is right .
they don't even you know how to even feed themselves .
tú sabes cómo están las cosas ahí afuera con los nenes ?
yo no voy a dejar que please .
no y tú viste que quiere ahora mi hija caminar sola al parque ?
le dije que no .
no .
por supuesto que no .
dice que con con veinte niños y y two or three parents .
maybe si van dos o tres parents and like maybe ten or fifteen kids .
I don't like this looseness .
I don't like it either sis .
trust me it' the hardest job .
yo te digo it' very hard .
it' very very hard .
that' why I rather her being with you for the summer .
yeah .
piénsalo bien .
no yo lo que hoy digo es que sí .
yo I pick up .
mañana habla con ella .
you know I figure I can give you maybe two hundred dollars a month .
do you think is that too little ?
yeah .
well whatever .
and then and then and then two hundred dollars a month for you and two hundred dollars to to do whatever .
the thing is ...
so it' four hundred dollars a month .
two hundred dollars for the expenses .
you know the food ...
we can calculate to see because cuando uno come afuera it' expensive .
well no two hundred dollars for her expenses for the food for the movies wherever you go .
yeah .
I think two hundred is ok@:eng .
or we could make it less than what we spend .
and then we make adjustments .
ok or we could that way .
I think that way is better .
you could just you could maybe that' another way of doing it .
yeah .
I give you the money for you .
and then whatever you spend you tell me .
right .
like we do with the stuff .
we put it on a yeah in a list .
and then do that way .
alright that would work .
that will work .
because I yo no quiero .
pero let let' let' see if she wants to do that .
.
es que mamá fue como que esta mañana se lo dijo .
y ayer también .
you know empezó .
mother told her or she told her ?
.
did mother bring it up or Carmencita@:eng brought it up ?
no she brought it up .
tú ves entonces se me va a fastidiar a mí porque es mi hija .
.
con las amistades .
no es que mami prefiere que ella vaya al parque .
no yo no quiero que vaya al parque .
pero mami prefiere .
no but I don't prefer it .
and I'm the mother .
yeah .
if we can keep it controlled sis .
no no you got to .
entonces mira yo mañana tú mañana vas a hacer proyecto con ella .
yeah .
mañana qué es ?
sábado ?
mañana mañana es viernes .
oh en viernes .
ella no tiene escuela .
oh yeah that'll be good .
ella no tiene escuela todo el día .
excellent .
tú si terminas la .
tú crees que puedas terminarlo mañana ?
it would be great if you can .
&=gasp .
it' a lot of work .
well .
sino you are gonna .
but we can we can .
no she' grounded on Saturday too so ...
we can ...
I don't like that .
but I would ...
I'd say let let' finish this quickly and maybe we can lift it .
now that' how I would work it .
you see what I'm talking about ?
psychology ?
yeah .
that that' that' turning it around .
well maybe that would work .
if she finishes all her project on Friday a lo mejor el sábado ella puede salir .
you know .
right .
or have a friend no salir tener una amiga en la casa .
you know no .
exactly .
tampoco yo no quiero .
no eso no .
pero that' how I I I was saying originally when we started this conversation yo te dije que I don't believe in punishment like that .
ok so that'll do good .
I mean she deserved she deserved .
well I've never in eleven years I've never punished her .
sure this is my first time punishing her .
but she deserves it she deserves it .
she has a big mouth .
tú sabes que yo nunca le le he dado un punishment a mi hija .
sí .
éste éste sería el primero en los años de existencia .
bueno .
pero es que a veces hay que hacerlo .
ya el el máximo .
ya ella se hizo el máximo .
no puede estar hablando así boberías .
no .
entonces vamos .
that' a good idea sis .
yeah .
that' what I said at the beginning .
te acuerdas que te dije ?
and then next week monday tiene que hacerlo los dientes .
going yeah .
te voy a dar un blind check .
ponles los braces .
ponles .
esa es otra cosa que le va a molestar toda el week .
well she wants some .
she wanted it on Thursday today .
she wants you to take her today porque she wants to show it to her friends .
really ?
oh my god .
no todos los niños los tienen .
.
well ese the good thing es que she is a kid .
it' like a fad right know with the kids .
and she wanted right away .
she said that she' not gonna give you hard time ni nada .
que no va a llorar ni nada .
ok good .
I'll say +"/.
+" you know what ?
+" I'll go outside .
so ponlo pónselo .
y entonces .
pero the last time she was so good .
ya .
she was so good when they were pulling out that tooth .
or they were filling it they were filling it .
she' big now .
now she' by herself .
oh yeah no she' very smart .
I said +"/.
+" mamita te aguanto la mano mamita ?
+" no I'm ok .
she' brilliant .
she' smart kid .
and she' very well loved .
they love her .
I said +"/.
+" ok .
doctor loves her .
pero she needs a braces up here .
aquí va a tener uno .
tiene tres dientes que le están se le van a salir me dijo .
I said +"/.
+" why don't you let me touch it ?
.
no because she said the last time I touched her I it .
what ?
I did .
&=gasp .
all of her teeth .
&=laugh but why you go back into her mouth and do it again &=laugh ?
I said I said +"/.
+" let me touch them .
+" let me see how .
ella no me deja .
ella no quiere que ni le toque el pelo .
ni que le toque los dientes .
.
no quiere .
antes que te vayas quiero que te enseñe .
si Tom@:eng no está ahí que te enseñe la parte cuando ella está caminando conmigo en el .
sí .
&=groan .
oye qué fantástico .
.
hasta me dio ganas de llorar .
ay no .
sí me dio ganas de llorar because .
she is growing up .
you know what these things really do happen .
of course .
you know and and .
you said only in the protection of the lord are we safe .
Moses I love you .
I love him with all my heart .
lets catch lunch .
.
how about eating some fish or@:eng something@:eng .
yeah to@:eng go@:eng .
I love that .
that' where I was yesterday .
I went to a fish restaurant .
bien rico es colombiano .
mm I love .
but they would they would .
yeah but I eat fish .
I mean you can have what ever you want .
but I mean I was just eating fish .